Car Sales Analysis Dashboard
Interactive Power BI Project Overview
This dashboard provides a comprehensive overview
of car sales performance
Key metrics include Total Sales, Total Cars,
Average Price, and Mileage
Users can interact with filters such as
Car Model and Year for dynamic analysis
Sales trends are visualized across multiple years
to identify performance patterns
Fuel type distribution highlights customer preferences
including petrol, diesel, hybrid, and electric vehicles
The Brand and Model Analysis page provides detailed insights
into individual vehicle performance
Users can filter specific car models
to explore their behavior across different years
Transmission analysis compares automatic
and manual vehicle preferences
Fuel type selection allows deeper understanding
of diesel, petrol, hybrid, and electric vehicles
Color trends and customer choices are visualized
to highlight popular selections
Additional insights include accident history,
vehicle features, and model-specific attributes
This showcases key automotive brands
featured in the dataset
It enables comparison of brand performance
across different market segments
These insights help identify strong brands
and their influence on overall sales
The Sales and Market Insights page focuses on
overall business performance
Key indicators include Total Sales,
Total Orders, and Average Price
Sales by condition highlights demand for
new, used, and like-new vehicles
Transmission and color analysis provide insights
into customer buying behavior
This dashboard demonstrates strong skills in
data visualization and analytics
It is designed to transform complex data
into clear and meaningful insights
Built using Power BI, DAX, and a custom JSON theme
for a clean and professional dashboard design
Thank you for watching